Guide to the William Hays Simpson Papers, 1915-1938.
Duke University. University Archives
William Hays Simpson papers 1915-1938
Duke University. University Archives
Simpson, William Hays, 1903-.
0.5 linear feet Extent: 100 Items
William Hays Simpson was a Professor of Political Science at Duke University from 1930 until 1974. His collection includes material concerning credits in North Carolina, which was one of Professor Simpson's research interests. Also includes reports, clippings, and correspondence. The collection ranges in date from 1915-1938.
uawhsimp
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The William Hays Simpson Papers, were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1973.
Biographical Note
William Hays Simpson was born in Madison Run, Virginia. He married Mary McNab in 1930. He received his A. B. degree from Tusculum College in Greenville, TN and his M. A. and Ph.D. degrees from Duke University. In 1930, he joined the faculty of Duke's political science department where his specialties were the American political system and Southern politics. He retired in 1974. His research interests included the social and economic life of cotton mill workers in Canada, Holland and England as well as consumer credit. He published several books, including The Small Loan Problem of the Carolinas (1941), Life in Mill Communities (1943) and Southern Textile Communities (1948). Professor Simpson died in 1989 at the age of 85.
Collection Overview
Contains material concerning credits in North Carolina, which was one of Professor Simpson's research interests. Also includes reports, clippings, and correspondence. The collection ranges in date from 1915-1938.
Subject Headings
Credit Unions -- History.; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.).; Simpson, William Hays, 1903-.
Related Material
News Service Biographical Files, 1960-2004.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 1 Box
  - Annual Reports, 1921-1940 (Box 1)
  - Biennial Reports, 1930-1934
  - Monthly Reports, 1916-1920
  - Progress, 1923
  - General, 1928
  - Early History-Carmel Credit Union, 1916
  - Progress of Movement, 1916
  - Summaries
  - NCCU, 1940
  - Early History-Propaganda of State Agricultural Extension Service, 1915-1916
  - Early History-Organization of First Credit Union, 1922-1923
  - Legislation, 1915-1926